so let's define the global and local hit
rate the global hit rate can be defined
as simply one minus the global miss rate
and the global miss rate can be defined
as the number of misses in this cache
divided by the number of all memory
references that the processor makes not
just those that reach this cache in
contrast the local hit rate and the
local miss rate can be defined in terms
of normal cache behavior local to this
cache so the local hit rate for example
is the number of hits divided by the
number of accesses to this cache and
remember that not all of the memory
references the processor makes actually
reach this cache the local miss rate
simply can be the number of misses
divided by the number of accesses and
they of course still add up to 1 another
popular metric of how often the cache
hits that tries to capture the behavior
of caches that are not the level 1 cache
is misses per thousand instructions or
MP ki where K stands for kilo
instructions it is very similar to the
global miss rate except that it doesn't
normalize the misses with the number of
just memory accesses it normalizes with
the number of instructions